Margaret Goddard Holt Papers, 1814-2004 (bulk 1960-2000)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES
  - Countries
    - Middle East
      - Israel (Arab-Israeli conflict)
        - Organizations and publications
          - Palestinian Human Rights Watch Newsletter 1987-88 (Box 91, Folder 7)
          - Shalom 1982-97 (Box 91, Folder 8)
          - Others 1980s-2000 (Box 91, Folder 9-13)
        - Clippings, articles, fliers, newsletters, and pamphlets, [see also Oversize Box 123]
          - 1960s-90s (Box 92, Folder 1-7)
          - 1990s-2004, undated (Box 93, Folder 1-8)
        - Vanunu, Mordechai, [see also Oversize Box 123]
          - "I Am Your Spy": newsletter 1994-2004 (Box 94, Folder 1)
          - Fliers and fundraising information 1993-2002, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
        - Lebanon: Israeli invasion 1985 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Southeast Asia
      - Korea 1990-91 (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - Philippines 1981 (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Vietnam War and aftermath, [see also AFSC: Russell Johnson]
        - General 1962-90s, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 94, Folder 6-7)
        - Cambodia 1966-91 (Box 94, Folder 8)
        - Laos 1970-71, undated (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Tibet 1991 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - USSR and Russia 1983-92 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - United Nations 1982-95 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Death, and choice in dying 1970s-2000s, undated (Box 94, Folder 13-14)
  - Death penalty, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE - Officials and elected representatives]
    - Generalcirca 1964-2000, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty: newsletters 1987-2001, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Abu-Jamal, Mumia
      - Correspondence 1995, undated (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Writings by Abu-Jamal and photographs 1982-99 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Legal documents, reports, and letters of support 1995 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Clippings 1994-95, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
      - Legal and political support
        - Committee to Save Mumia Abu-Jamal 1995-96 (Box 95, Folder 8)
        - Equal Justice USA (Quixote Center)
          - Correspondence and forms 1992-95, undated (Box 95, Folder 9)
          - Newsletters and fliers 1995-97, undated (Box 96, Folder 1)
        - International Action Center 2000 (Box 96, Folder 2)
        - International Committee of Concerned Family and Friends of Mumia Abu-Jamal 1995, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
        - Partisan Defense Committee 1989-95 (Box 96, Folder 4)
        - Refuse and Resist 1999-2000 (Box 96, Folder 5)
        - Massachusetts groups 1995-99, undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
      - Publication: Jamal Journal 1994-95, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 96, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, notes, fliers, and reports 1991-2000, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Gilbert, Kristen: clippings 2000-01 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Economics
    - International and United States: articles and clippings 1985-2004 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Massachusetts
      - General economic and tax reform 1983-89, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - General economic and tax reform 1990-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Citizens for Fair Taxes
        - Agendas, minutes, and notes 1989-91, undated (Box 97, Folder 2)
        - Notescirca 1989 (Box 97, Folder 3)
        - Clippings, correspondence, press releases, mission statements, and financial information 1989-90, undated (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Education 1990, undated (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Elder citizens, [see also SERIES IV. ACTIVISM - Gray Panthers, and Oversize Box 123]
    - General 1984-91, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Day care for elder citizens 1992, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Massachusetts Department of Elder Affairs 1984-88, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Northampton (Massachusetts) Elder Americans 1986 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Older Women's League 1989-94, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Environment
    - General 1967-95, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Massachusetts 1989-95, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Farming and land conservation 1985-91 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation 1988-91 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Feminism and women's rights, [see also Reproductive rights, and Oversize Box 123]
    - 1977-89 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - 1990-99, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Gay and lesbian rights: clippings, and fliers 1989-90, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Healthcare
    - General 1985-92, undated (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Coalition for Medicaid Access 1986-87 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Disability issues 1984-91, undated (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - MassHealth Action Alliance 1984-90, undated (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Human rights
    - General 1977-2001, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - ARISE for Social Justice 1990-95, undated (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Haymarket People's Fund: grant application formsundated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Hunger 1984-90, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Labor rights
    - General 2001-03, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - United Farm Workers 1985-91, undated (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Landmines 1994-2003 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Media: Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) 1989-90 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - Military
    - War resistance, and conscientious objection to military service 1990-91, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Enlistment and recruitment 1983, undated (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Military spending 1985-2001, undated (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Pacifismcirca 1985-89 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Veterans 1981-2001, undated (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Westover Air Force Base (Massachusetts): C-5A flyover controversy 1987-90 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Music
    - Concert programs, and musical score for The Messiah 1912-99, undated (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro: articles 1957, undated, [see also Artwork] (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Nuclear power and waste, chemical waste, and radiation 1991-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Peace and disarmament, [see also Middle East - Gulf War and Iraq War, and Organizations]
    - General 1941-89, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 99, Folder 10-12)
    - General 1990-2003, undated (Box 100, Folder 1-4)
    - Berrigan, Daniel and Philip Berrigan 1971-2002, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Hiroshima and Nagasaki 1970-2002, undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Massachusetts, Western
      - Peace and disarmament directoriesundated (Box 100, Folder 7)
      - Peace Pagoda 1985-90 (Box 100, Folder 8)
      - Pioneer Valley War Tax Resisters 1989-91 (Box 100, Folder 9)
      - Traprock Peace Center 1988-91, undated (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Organizations
      - American Friends Service Committee
        - General 1970-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
        - Johnson, Russell 1965-78, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - Martin Luther King Day (Northampton, Massachusetts) 1988-91, undated (Box 101, Folder 4)
      - Center for Defense Information 1983-91 (Box 101, Folder 5)
      - Committee for Nuclear Responsibility 1990-2000 (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - Committee on Common Security 1988-90, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 101, Folder 7)
      - Fellowship of Reconciliation 1981-91 (Box 101, Folder 8)
      - International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War 1988-90, undated (Box 101, Folder 9)
      - Jobs With Peace 1985-91 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      - Peace Council of the German Democratic Republic 1989 (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Plowshares Defense Fund 1991 (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - War Resister's League 1982-2002, undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
      - Witness for Peace 1990-91, undated, [see also Central America] (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom 1971-91 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - World Federalist Association 1989-95, undated (Box 102, Folder 6)
      - World Friendship Center 1984-94 (Box 102, Folder 7)
      - World Peacemakers, Inc. 1988-90 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Peace Pilgrim 2003, undated (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Women for Peace: pilgrimage to Rome
      - Biographical information, correspondence, clippings, notes, photographs, and memorabilia, b 1963-64 (Box 102, Folder 10)
      - Brochures and printed materials 1963 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Strategic Defense Initiative ("Star Wars") 1984-90, undated (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy, religion and spirituality
    - General 2003, undated (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Buddhismundated (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Catholicism 1957-2003, undated (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Islam 1987-97, undated (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Taoism (LaoTsu)undated (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Unitarian Universalism
      - General 1978-91, undated (Box 103, Folder 6)
      - First Unitarian Universalist Church, Springfield, MA 1954-87, undated (Box 103, Folder 7-8)
    - Other 1984-2001, undated (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Politics
    - International and national
      - General 1950-2003, undated (Box 103, Folder 10-13)
      - Jackson, Jesse 1987-88, undated (Box 14)
    - Massachusetts
      - General 1983-2001, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - Western Massachusetts
        - General 1980-2001, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 104, Folder 2)
        - Directory for Research on the Pioneer Valley by Wendy Sibbison, ed. 1983 (Box 104, Folder 3)
        - Political campaigns
          - Olver, John 1989-91, undated (Box 104, Folder 4)
          - Rosenberg, Stan 1989-91, undated (Box 104, Folder 5)
          - Wentworth, Mary 1984, 2001, undated (Box 104, Folder 6)
          - Other candidates 1989-2001, undated (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - Political organizations
        - Christic Institute 1987-89, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 104, Folder 8)
        - Citizens for Participation in Political Action 1988-92, undated (Box 104, Folder 9)
        - Committee of Correspondence 1994-95 (Box 104, Folder 10)
        - People for the American Way 1986-91 (Box 104, Folder 11)
        - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation 1981-90, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 104, Folder 12)
        - RESIST 1982-2004 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Poverty 1988-96, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Prison reform, crime, and gun control
    - General 1978-2002, undated (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Organizations
      - Fortune Society 1990-2001, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - Prison Connections 1996-97 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - Southern Coalition on Jails and Prisons 1989-90 (Box 105)
  - Psychoanalysis
    - General 1953-78 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Eissler, K.R: writings 1963-75 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Jung, C.G.: Jung Seminar notes, Bailey Island, Maine 1936 (Box 105)
  - Racism 1975-91, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Reproductive rights 1972-97, undated (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Social Security 1985-88 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Terrorism 1981, 2001 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "Osborn Express": Springfield, Mass. school newsletter 1977 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Other 1933-2004, undated (Box 106)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Biographical materials
    - Margaret Holt: awards, oversize clipping, posters, memorabilia and developmental profile chart, photograph by Diana Jo Davies, and photo montages 1963-2002, [see also Oversize Box 108] (Box 107)
    - Lee E. Holt: articles and clippings 1961-77 (Box 107)
  - Correspondence
    - Lee, Matthew: Inner City Press 1988-92 (Box 107)
    - Other: cloth greeting card 2000 (Box 107)
  - Activism
    - Grey Panthers: scrapbook 1984-85 (Box 108)
    - Vigils: clippings, posters, and scrapbook 1982, 2000, undated (Box 108)
  - Artwork
    - By others
      - Kollwitz, Kathe: "Six Drawings" (portfolio)undated (Box 108)
      - Speight, Francis: sketches of Margaret Holt 1932 (includes related correspondence by Sarah Speight, 1990) (Box 108)
    - By Margaret Holt
      - Oil paintingsundated (Box 109)
      - Sketchbooks 1972-86, undated (Box 110)
      - Watercolor paintings; and sketches in pen, ink, and charcoal 1930s-80s (Box 111-112)
  - Photographs
    - Margaret Holt
      - 80th Birthday Party 1991 (Box 113)
      - Photomontages of Margaret Holtundated (Box 113)
    - Lee E. Holt: Navy group photographundated (Box 113)
    - Fanny Whiting Reed Goddardcirca 1935 (Box 114)
    - Interior views of Margaret Holt's childhood home in Swarthmore, PAundated (Box 114)
    - "Moisey Moesevitch, beloved Goddart [sic] cat" undated (Box 114)
    - Albums
      - Goddard family, and Margaret and Lee Holt with childrencirca 1900-43 (Box 115)
      - Goddard familycirca 1881-1910 (Box 115)
      - After marriage of Margaret Goddard and Lee E. Holt 1939-41 (Box 115)
      - Holt family 1929-31 (Box 116)
      - Margaret Holt with children, Geoffrey Holt and Alison Holt 1940s (Box 116)
      - Geoffrey Holt and Alison Holt as infants and toddlers 1940s (Box 117)
      - Florence Conecirca 1908-27 (Lee E. Holt's sister) (Box 118)
      - Lee E. Holt's family
        - General
          - Circa 1919-21 (Box 119)
          - Circa 1924-26 (Box 120)
          - undated (Box 121)
        - Europecirca 1926-27 (Box 122)
  - Subject files
    - Affordable housing and homelessness: Perkins PressApr 1990 (Box 123)
    - Countries
      - Central America
        - General: various publications 1987-94 (Box 123)
        - El Salvador: Neighbor to Neighbor Action Projectundated (Box 123)
        - Guatemala: What About Guatemala?undated (Box 123)
        - Nicaragua: Valley Women's Voice, and New England Human Rights Network 1983 (Box 123)
      - Middle East
        - Iraq: various publications re: Gulf War 1991 (Box 123)
        - Israel
          - Organizations: printed materials and newsletters 1980s-2003 (Box 123)
          - Vanunu, Mordcai: The Catholic WorkerOct/Nov 1993 (Box 123)
      - Vietnam: "Do You Know These Facts? Do You Support Them?," New York Review of Books 1967 (Box 123)
    - Death penalty
      - Publication: New PatriotJune 1990 (Box 123)
      - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty: Lifelines 1990-2001 (Box 123)
      - Abu-Jamal, Mumia
        - Petition in Philadelphia Daily NewsAug 1995 (Box 123)
        - Postersundated (Box 123)
        - Publications
          - Jamal Journal 1994-95 (Box 123)
          - Others 1995 (Box 123)
    - Economic issues in Massachusetts: publications 1986-95 (Box 123)
    - Elder citizens: publications 1985-94 (Box 123)
    - Environment: New England Sierran 1989-92 (Box 123)
    - Feminism: publications 1977-90 (Box 123)
    - Gay and lesbian rights: Left Field 1990 (Box 123)
    - Human rights and social justice: publicationsundated (Box 123)
    - Hunger
      - The Hunger Project: A Shift in the Wind 1983-88 (Box 123)
      - Institute for Food and Development Policy: Hunger Myths and Factsundated (Box 123)
    - King, Martin Luther, Jr.: poster 1990 (Box 123)
    - Nuclear power and waste: publications 1993, 2003 (Box 123)
    - Peace and disarmament
      - Berrigan, Daniel and Philip Berrigan: clippings 2001-02 (Box 123)
      - Miscellaneous publications 1970-90 (Box 123)
    - Politics
      - General: fliercirca 1995 (Box 123)
      - Western Massachusetts: fliercirca 1995 (Box 123)
      - Organizations
        - Christic Institute: The People's Daily 1987 (Box 123)
        - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation: flier 1981 (Box 123)
    - Poverty: Spare Change 1996 (Box 123)
    - Prison reform, crime, and gun control: publications 1990 (Box 123)
    - Racism: posterundated (Box 123)